Hello, English learners. Welcome to English
Pod. My name is Marco and I'm Erica.
And today we're back bringing you another
great lesson and an intermediate lesson.
That's right, about one of my favorite
subjects, we're talking about food.
Exactly. So on this
occasion we're going to be
talking about food, so
let's preview some words
on vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret-y preview.
All right, we have three
words for you today.
And the first word is head chef. Head chef.
Head chef. So what is a head chef?
Well, in a professional
kitchen, this is the
boss of the kitchen or
the leader of the kitchen.
Okay, so the head chef is the main cook.
Yes, but he doesn't cook.
But he doesn't cook.
Okay. All right, so if he
doesn't cook, who's the
one that does the cooking?
That brings us to our
second word, sous chef.
sous chef. So the s is
silent because it's like a
French word. Yeah,
something like that. Okay.
So the sous chef is the
second in line to the head.
Yeah, he's the number
two. Number two.
So he's basically the one that's
doing some of the work in the kitchen.
Yep. Now let's take a look at our
last word, cuisine. Cuisine. Cuisine.
So this is an interesting word.
What exactly does it mean? Well,
it basically means cooking, right?
Okay. Like the art of cooking. So
for example, I can say French food.
Yeah, or French cuisine. French
cuisine, which includes all the food. Yeah.
And this is also the major that people
study in college to become a chef. Yep.
The study cuisine. And
cuisine is a noun, right?
It's a noun. Okay, so I
think we're ready to dive
into our dialogue.
What exactly is going on?
Well, we're in a restaurant
and it's a really busy night.
And so we're going to listen to
what is happening in the kitchen.
Right away, sir, your
order will be ready shortly.
John, we have another
special for table seven.
I'm working as fast as I can.
We are willing the weeds.
Where is my spaceship? Look,
I need you to pick them
up. But they don't have a
mario, chips and onions
and carrots for the stew.
From here, another special. We're really
packed tonight. We're running low on wine.
Is there any left in the
salon? Sorry I'm late, everyone.
Wow, we're really
doing well tonight.
Hi, stop talking
and get over here.
I need some soothed tea,
and the fish needs to be but
chilled and buttered.
Okay, how about it?
John, yeah, table seven has
requested to see the chef.
I think there are food
critics from cuisine, magazine.
Okay, so a busy night
here at this restaurant.
I know, it sounds
like there's a lot of
pressure on this chef
here. Yeah, you can tell
in his voice that he's
really stressed out.
Yep. Okay, let's take a
look at some of this kitchen
vocabulary that we found
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, well, we've got
five words for you
today. In the first one is
peel, peel, peel, peel, P-E-E-L.
So this is a verb, and it means
to remove the outside skin.
Okay, so for example, when you're going
to eat a banana, you must peel it first.
You must peel it. You got
to take away the yellow skin.
What else do you
peel? Oranges, potatoes,
potatoes, like in the dialogue. What
else can you peel? I don't know, carrots.
Carrots. Some people peel their tomatoes. I
don't know why. Yeah, it is kind of weird.
All right, now let's take a look at
our next word, chop, chop, chop.
So again, another verb, and it
means to cut food into pieces.
Oh, so if you're
going to eat carrots,
first you got to chop them. Exactly. Right,
you can put a whole carrot in your soup,
in your soup, in your
rice. Yeah. Okay, chop.
Okay, our next word,
stirred. Yeah, this is the
past participle
of the word stir.
Okay, so the verb stir. Stir.
So when you stir something,
imagine you have a
big pot, and you've got a
long spoon, you move
the spoon around in circles.
Okay. So you're
stirring the pot.
You're mixing. Mm-hmm.
To stir is very similar to mix.
Yes. Okay, so you just
move the food around.
Move the food around.
Okay, our next word, butchered.
Again, the past participle of the verb
butchered. Okay, butchered. Butchered. Now,
this a verb to butcher
something. Mm-hmm.
It's when you remove all the bones
and all the organs from the meat.
Exactly. So you cut up the meat.
And this is interesting
because it's also a noun.
Right, a butcher is a
person who cuts up meat.
Okay, so it's really easy. A
butcher butchered's meat.
Yes. All right, our last
word, butter. Buttered.
Buttered. Buttered. Okay,
so buttered, this is weird.
I know. Normally,
we all know the noun
buttered, but here it's
acting as a verb. Okay.
So when you butter something,
you spread or put butter on it.
Okay. So to put
butter on something.
So you can butter a
piece of bread. Exactly.
Or in this case, the fish is
being buttered. Mm-hmm.
Sounds delicious. Okay, now we're ready to
listen to our dialogue for the second time.
We're going to slow it down a
little bit so it's easier to understand.
Right away, sir.
Your order will be ready shortly.
Jump here. We have another special for
table seven. I'm working as fast as I can.
We are really in the weeds.
Where is my sushi? Look, I
need you to peel more potatoes.
Marie.
Chop some onions and carrots for the stew.
I sip up with sea blouse on the mama.
Strong pair on all special.
We're really packed tonight.
We're running raw on wine.
Is there any left in the cellar?
Whoa, sorry. I'm late, everyone. Wow.
We are really doing well tonight.
Ah, stop talking and come
over here. I need to be so
stirred and the fish needs
to be buttered and buttered.
Okay, I'm on it.
Jump here.
Table seven has requested to see the chef.
I think they are food critics
from cuisine magazine.
Okay, so that seems to be
a little bit better. Mm-hmm.
And hey, I noticed that
there's a lot of really
great kitchen words
in here, like words that
you commonly hear in
a professional kitchen.
Okay, so let's take a look
at these kitchen words in
fluency builder. Fluency builder.
All right, we've got three phrases.
And the first one is in
the weeds. In the weeds.
In the weeds. So when
you're in the weeds,
you're so, so busy and you can't do
all the work you need to do on time.
Okay, so in the weeds, it
means that you're really busy. Yes.
And you can't finish everything. And
you can't, you have too much to do. Yeah.
Okay, in the weeds.
Okay, our next word,
running low on, running
low on, running low on.
Okay, so before we get
into explaining what running
low on means, let's
listen to some examples.
Example one. You better look for a
gas station. We're running low on fuel.
Example two. We're running low on beers.
Can you go out and get some?
Example three. My flashlight is running low
on battery. Hurry up before it gets dark.
So basically running low means
you don't have much of this left.
You don't have much
of something left.
Yeah, so here they're running
low on wine. So basically,
there's not much
wine left. Right.
So as we heard in the examples,
you could also be running
low on fuel, for example, on
your car, et cetera, running low on.
All right. And now
let's take a look
at our last word, doing
really well, doing really well.
We are doing really
well, doing really well.
So this seems to be like
a pretty simple structure.
I mean, we know all
these words, right?
Mm-hmm. So why is it special?
Well, basically, if you
say I am doing really well,
maybe it sounds a little bit difficult to
understand. What are you doing really well?
So this is a great way
of answering a question.
When somebody says, how
are you, or how are you doing,
you can say, oh,
I'm doing really well.
So I'm doing well. In your
life, everything is good.
In your life, things are good
and you're happy, basically.
Yeah. But in this
situation, in the dialogue,
what's doing really well?
Well, the restaurant is
doing really well. The
business is doing really well.
So when he says,
we're doing really well,
business is good. Good.
They're making lots of money.
Exactly. So you can
use it with people.
You can use it with
businesses. You can say, oh,
I'm doing really well
in my new job. Yep.
Or my son is doing
really well in school. Yep.
Okay. So you can use it
in those different ways.
All right. Well, let's
listen to the dialogue
one last time and we'll
be able to hear all of
these great words and
phrases we just talked about.
Right away, sure, your
order would be ready shortly.
John, we have another
special for table seven.
I'm working as fast as I can.
We are leading the weeds.
Where is my spaceship?
Look, I need you to
pick them up with details.
Ma'i, chaps them on your
hands and call us photos to you.
From here, another special, we're really
patched tonight. We're running low on wine.
There's the one
he left in the cello.
Sorry, I'm late, everyone. Wow,
we're really doing well tonight.
Hi. Dr. King and get over here.
I need some still and the fish
needs to be butchered and buttered.
Okay. How about it?
Jean Pierre, table seven has
requested to see the chef.
I think there are food
critics from cuisine, magazine.
So Marco, do you
think this chef had a rat
under his house? That
was a really good movie.
I had a two-e that Disney
Pixar, where a rat is a cook.
Yes. It's interesting. I love to cook,
but I'm not very good at cooking. Really?
But it's good because for
me, it helps me relieve stress.
Me too, actually. You
know, if I'm in a bad
mood, I go home and
cook something to eat and
the world seems a happier place.
And people don't understand
it because they think cooking is
work, but for some
people, it's fun. Yeah.
So what about you guys?
What do you like to cook?
Do you have any particular
dish that you prepare very well?
And if you do, please
send us the recipe.
Exactly because we know
that we have listeners
from all over the world and of course, we
want to know what type of food you prefer.
So come to EnglishPod.com
and post your questions,
your comments, and your
recipes in our community section.
And Eric and I will
always be there.
Yes, to test out your recipes
as well as answer questions.
For sure. If good
recipe comes along,
we'll prepare it and we'll let
you know how it turned out.
Yeah. All right, guys.
We're out of time,
but we'll see you next time.
Until then. Goodbye.